

tking3612@gmail.com | 678-332-4542 | Woodstock, GA 30188

## **Summary**

I am studying as a user-minded Web Developer, prioritizing usability and adaptability during projects. I am ambitious, career-focused, and anxious to obtain an entry-level Software Engineer position to help launch my career while achieving company goals. I am working towards mastering the skills of an Adaptable Software Engineer, ready to support operations from conception through post-release support. Skilled Creator of efficient code and exciting user experiences. Eager to elevate ongoing development projects or create novel software solutions to drive increased usership. I am a professional with an outstanding background in applying a strong work ethic to perform my position's duties. I am a committed employee with a history of meeting company needs with consistent and organized practices. Seven years of expertise in building construction, maintenance, and remodeling have shaped me into a successful creator. I offer progressive experience in owning web-based projects from concept and design through testing, implementation, and client updates.

## **Education and Training**

General Assembly, **Software Engineer** Certificate of Completion – Software Engineering Immersive January 2023

<u>Languages:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

<u>Libraries:</u> jQuery

Framework: BootStrap, React

## Skills

- Highly motivated employee with a desire to take on new challenges.
- Strong worth ethic, adaptability, and exceptional interpersonal skills.
- Diligent in producing exceptionally clean, strong, and secure code.
- Successful at achieving browser, device, and operating system compatibility objectives while satisfying client desires and producing robust, sophisticated designs.
- Comfortable working within large-scale collaborations or on individually developed assets.

- Skilled in working under pressure and adapting to new situations and challenges to best enhance the organizational brand.
- Hardworking and reliable Software Engineer with strong ability in software development.
- Highly organized, proactive, and punctual with a team-oriented mentality.
- Adept at working effectively unsupervised and quickly mastering new skills.
- Intelligent in planning tasks by performing simple and complex calculations.

## Experience

Woodland Steelworks **Carpenter**07/2020 - Present

Builder King Carpenter 06/2018 - 06/2020

Chappell Construction Group Carpenter 01/2015 - 06/2018

- Manufacture household furniture and outdoor furniture.
- Manufacture large furniture projects.
- Operate CNC machine for production.
- Design new products and improve production methods.
- Organize and manage materials for production.
- Punctual Carpenter with extensive knowledge of wood quality and composition.
- Collaborates successfully with homeowners in selecting building materials.
- Strictly adheres to building plans to promote customer satisfaction and return business.
- Provides high-quality carpentry through precise and detailoriented approaches.
- Driven to exceed customer expectations while meeting all budget and schedule requirements.
- Regularly leads helpers and instructs less experienced professionals in basic and advanced techniques.
- Responsibilities included installing flooring, cabinetry, and tile, managing project designs and materials, property management, and overseeing remodels.
- Safety-minded in following procedures, maintaining organized workspaces, and using tools correctly.
- Displayed keen attention to detail and design.
- Recognizes customer service as a valuable tool to deliver quality and satisfaction.
- Committed to fulfilling all customer expectations through careful adherence to design plans and requests.
- Responsibilities included labor work, trim carpentry, heavy machinery, cleaning job sites, and demolition.
- Knowledgeable and skilled in various construction techniques, procedures, carpentry tools, and equipment.
- Team-oriented in communicating with others to complete excellent rough carpentry work and share information needed to finish carpentry tasks.
- Versatile Carpenter with seven years of experience on various construction sites, including several new home developments.
- Completes tasks on time and with little guidance.
- Successful at guaranteeing client satisfaction through meticulous and long-lasting work.
- Efficient Carpenter equipped with tools necessary to complete tasks on time and with little guidance.

Website, Portfolios, and Profiles	

- Website/Portfolio: <a href="https://dash.generalassemb.ly/Taylor\_King/build-your-own-personal-website">https://dash.generalassemb.ly/Taylor\_King/build-your-own-personal-website</a>
- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/taylor-king-se